<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Ogden Studios</title>
    <link>/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Ogden Studios</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Students for Sensible Drug Policy</title>
      <link>/projects/ssdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/ssdp/</guid>
      <description>Students for Sensible Drug Policy maintained an in-house WordPress website from about 2012-2016. From 2015-2016, I was in charge of maintaining the blog posts, users, and updates of that WordPress installation. Over the 2015-2016 program year, the organization hired a third party contractor to redesign and rebuild our website, and the results were ultimately unsatisfactory.
After some initial security and usability problems with the final product, I was able to get the site to a stable state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THC Staffing Group</title>
      <link>/projects/tsg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/tsg/</guid>
      <description>THC Staffing Group is an organization dedicated to closing the gap between America’s rapidly growing cannabis industry and diverse, qualified employment candidates. For the past year, I&amp;rsquo;ve provided copy-editing, WordPress maintenance, WCAG AA compliance work, and a full rebuild for them. The current website is their legacy WordPress installation while we develop a full rebuild using Hugo. You can find the rebuild repository here and view progress at https://tsg.netlify.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Atwater Group</title>
      <link>/projects/atwater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/atwater/</guid>
      <description>The Atwater Group offers proofreading and editing services - all at affordable rates. We built a custom site for them using the Hugo static site generator and Netlify. You can view the code here</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>