<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ogden Studios</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ogden Studios</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Students for Sensible Drug Policy</title>
      <link>/projects/ssdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/ssdp/</guid>
      <description>Students for Sensible Drug Policy maintained an in-house WordPress website from about 2012-2016. From 2015-2016, I was in charge of maintaining the blog posts, users, and updates of that WordPress installation. Over the 2015-2016 program year, the organization hired a third party contractor to redesign and rebuild our website, and the results were ultimately unsatisfactory.
After some initial security and usability problems with the final product, I was able to get the site to a stable state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSDP Chapter Activity Tracker</title>
      <link>/projects/cat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/cat/</guid>
      <description>The SSDP Chapter Activity Tracker (CAT) is an online interface for SSDP chapters to log the activities they are engaging in. When chapters log activity on the CAT, they earn CAT points. CAT points can be spent on SSDP materials, conference registrations, and other items that help support their work. The CAT is a way to earn resources (that would otherwise cost money) by logging activism and giving us a deeper insight in how our chapters do their work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Atwater Group</title>
      <link>/projects/atwater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/atwater/</guid>
      <description>The Atwater Group offers proofreading and editing services - all at affordable rates. We built a custom site for them using the Hugo static site generator and Netlify. You can view the code here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THC Staffing Group</title>
      <link>/projects/tsg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/tsg/</guid>
      <description>THC Staffing Group is an organization dedicated to closing the gap between America’s rapidly growing cannabis industry and diverse, qualified employment candidates. For the past year, I&amp;rsquo;ve provided copy-editing, WordPress maintenance, WCAG AA compliance work, and a full rebuild for them. The current website is their legacy WordPress installation while we develop a full rebuild using Hugo. You can find the rebuild repository here and view progress at https://tsg.netlify.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Week in Drugs</title>
      <link>/projects/twid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/twid/</guid>
      <description>In 2015, I co-founded the This Week in Drugs podcast. Over the course of the last three years, I&amp;rsquo;ve provided a variety of services to the podcast organization, including audio editing, web design, web administration, and podcast publishing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Frank Lucido</title>
      <link>/projects/lucido/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/lucido/</guid>
      <description>I provide some basic tech support and web administration for Dr. Frank Lucido&amp;rsquo;s WordPress installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Design</title>
      <link>/projects/emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/emails/</guid>
      <description>I design and implement SSDP Email blasts using the MailJet Markup Language, converting it to HTML, and managing our email service provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;quot;HTML&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;JSON&amp;quot;]  Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>